## Software Engineer

\_

#### Contact me

Telephone: +61 459 323 826 Email: pro@yoni-firroloni.com

GitHub:

https://github.com/Vagahbond

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/yoni-firroloni-a5002b153/

#### Yoni FIRROLONI

38 Earl St, Roseville, NSW

#### **Profile**

French Software Engineer with 5 years of working experience, that moved to Australia with a work holiday visa.

My target is now to get sponsored for a work visa so that I can stay for a few years. In exchange, I am willing to create value using my rich experience and knowledge.

Note that I am able and willing to move from NSW if necessary.

Formerly a freelancer, I got a Software Architect Master's degree at ESGI, A parisian Computer Science engineer school.

#### **Skills**

Languages and frameworks:

- NodeJs(React, Nextjs, Nestjs, TS, Electron...)
- C/C++
- Ruby/Ruby on Rails
- HTML/CSS/JS
- PostgreSQL, MongoDB

### Experience

#### ESIEE (Graduate School)/Assistant Lecturer

September 2023 until January 2024, Noisy-Le-Grand, Nation

Supervising assignments and practice for a coworker's C and C++ language courses

#### Other tools:

- Git/TortoiseSVN
- GH Action, Gitlab CI
- GNU/Linux
- Docker/dockercompose
- Github Actions
- Kubernetes
- nix/NixOS
- NginX/Apache
- On-premise hosting

#### ESGI (Private engineer school)/Professor

September 2022 until April 2024, Paris, Nation

Teaching several topic to a multitude of different groups of students with different specializations.

Courses are in a bachelor's degree program and included:

- The C language (beginner and advanced)
- Developing APIs with NodeJS and ExpressJS
- Web Architecture (Apache centered course)
- Web and API (Theoric course on how to build RESTful APIs)
- Introduction to open source development

This experience implies overseeing theory and practice on those courses.

#### Methods:

- REST APIs
- Agile development
- Test Driven
  Development
- SOLID
- Hexagonal/Clean Architecture

#### Usual coding environment:

Linux, Neovim, VSCode

#### Soft skills:

Good adaptation

 Wide surface knowledge of IT in generall

- Passionated
- Able to teach and explain to non-technical stakeholders

#### **Keyros**/Software developer (Started as apprenticeship)

August 2020 until Semptember 2023, Saint Mandé (France)

Development of a crisis management application, using relational and graph DB, React, Ruby on Rails, and Python.

Decisions and design of features in a company of only 3 people.

CI/CD and production environment management with usage of docker.

#### Actual languages:

- French (native)
- English (Fluent, Toeic)

#### H3 HITEMA/Professor

March 2023 Issy-les-Moulineaux (France)

Teaching Nodejs/Express development to a master's degree class.

#### **Hobbies and interests**

- Music (Guitar and Computer assisted)
- Sport (Parkour, climbing, trekking and calisthenics)

#### **Newrest Wagons Lits/**Software engineer

(Apprenticeship)

September 2019 to July 2020, PARIS, 17e

NWL is a subsidiary of Newrest, catering company that has a network of 3,200 employees around the world.

#### Referees

Frédéric Sananes, current educational director at ESGI: fsananes@esgi.fr

Misison included retro-engineering an old ERP coded in Java with the help of scripting, and developing android apps using Android Studio.

#### **ABECEDAIRE**/Software developer(Internship)

January 2019 to Febuary 2019, ROUEN (France)

Erwan Jossic, current CTO at Keyros:

erwan.jossic@keyros.org

Web development with JS, JQuery, HTML, CSS, SQL and DreamWeaver

Technology watch

Further references available on request.

Debuts as a freelancer

#### **IDEA Informatique**/Software developer(Internship)

June 2018 to July 2018, EVREUX (France)

Development of an ERP's features with PL-SQL an Delphi on Embarcadero, using TortoiseSVN as a SVN.

\_\_\_

# Other teaching experiences

#### C week:

As a student, coaching other student and giving them exercises and katas during a themed C week in 2020 and 2021 at ESGI.

#### Dev day:

Conference about audio fingerprinting during the DevDay, in 2021 at ESGI

#### **Education**

ESGI/Master's degree - Software Architecture

October 2019 to July 2022, PARIS 12e

Bachelor's degree followed with a master's degree on Software Architecture.

This diploma includes year-long apprentice-ship with France's "alternance" system.

This specific curriculum includes a lot of diversity in terms of knowledge and allows having wide views on projects.

**Lycée Saint Adjutor**/Higher national certificate – Software Development

September 2017 to July 2019, VERNON

French "BTS" corresponding to Australian Higher national certificate, including necessary knowledge to become a developer and be efficient as part of a team in a company.

**Lycée Modest Leroy**/High school degree with engineer specialization